HARI V

Walajabad, TN 631605 631605, Kanchipuram, TN | 822 093 3521 | vhari.b.e@gmail.com |

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vhari01

Professional Summary

Managed Multi Process consistently rewarded for success in planning and operational improvements. Experience in policy development and staff management procedures positively impacting overall morale and productivity.

Skills

> Production Control

> Waste controls

> Production scheduling

> Material control

> Plant Management

Work History

Head-Operations. 12/2020 to Current

Chennai CNC Sevotronics Pvt Ltd – Kanchipuram, Tamilnadu

- 1. Provide inspired leadership for the organization.
- 2. Make important policy, planning, and strategy decisions.
- 3. Develop, implement, and review operational policies and procedures.
- 4. Assist HR with recruiting when necessary.
- 5. Help promote a company culture that encourages top performance and high morale.
- 6. Oversee budgeting, reporting, planning, and auditing.
- 7. Ensure all legal and regulatory documents are filed and monitor compliance with laws and regulations.
- 8. Work with the board of directors to determine values and mission, and plan for short and long-term goals.
- 9. Support worker communication with the management team.

Assistant Manager Production Control.

Chennai CNC Sevotronics Pvt Ltd – Kanchipuram, Tamilnadu

01/2019 to 11/2020

- 1. Coordinate production workflow for one or multiple products
- 2. Plan and prioritize operations to ensure maximum performance and minimum delay
- 3. Determine manpower, equipment and raw materials needed to cover production demand
- 4. Assign workers and other staff to particular production operations
- 5. Schedule shift according to production needs

- 6. Monitor jobs to ensure they will finish on time and within budget
- 7. Address issues when they arise aiming for minimum disruption
- 8. Obtain output information (number of finished products, percentage of defectives etc.)
- 9. Prepare and submit status and performance reports

Production Planning Control Engineer

10/2017 to 12/2018

Chennai CNC Servotronics Pvt Ltd. – Kanchipuram, Tamilnadu

- 1. Prepare Monthly Production Plan For All Machines Based on Customer Schedule.
- 2. Maintain Sufficient Stock In FG For Delivery
- 3. Coordinate Sales, Purchase, Production, Store & Tool Room.
- 4. Strategic planning to meet the production & quality targets.
- 5. To solve the all manufacturing issue at shop floor.
- 6. Implemented KAIZENs and continuous improvement related to cost, quality, process improvements and house-keeping.

Junior Engineer 08/2016 to 09/2017

Yushin India Automotive Pvt Ltd – Kanchipuram, Tamilnadu

- 1. Shift Production Planning In charge.
- 2. Ensure 4M for Production Activity
- 3. Daily Make Production Plan vs Actual Report.
- 4. Daily Make Production Downtime Report & Taking Actions Against Downtime.
- 5. Monthly Over all Equipment Efficiency Calculation.

Graduate Engineer Trainee

05/2015 to 07/2016

Yushin India Automotive Pvt Ltd – Kanchipuram, Tamilnadu

- 1. Analyzing the Production Reports Daily.
- 2. Responsible For Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP).
- 3. Preparing and Implementing action Plans effectively to maximize overall equipments efficiency of production machines.

Education

Master Degree : Master of Buisness Administration

Alagappa University – Karaikudi 05/2021 to Present

Bachelor Degree: B.E Mechanical Engineering 04/2015

Lord Ayyappa Inst Of Engg & Tech - Walajabad

Higher Secondary 03/2011

WTMM Higher Secondary School – Walajabad

Personnel Details

Father's Name :- K.VARATHAN

Permanent Address: - 75, Vinayagar koilst, Neikuppam village,

Avalur post, Walajabad-631605

Date of Birth :- 3 rdApril1994
 Language Known :- English & Tamil

Marital Status :- Married

Nationality/Religion :- Indian / Hindu

> Interest & Hobbies :- Internet browsing , Chatting, Cricket and Football.

Decleration

I do hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Signature
Date: (HARI V)